His story changed history.
The Irishman is a crime, drama, history film directed by Martin Scorsese.
Pennsylvania, 1956.
Frank Sheeran, a war veteran of Irish origin who works as a truck
driver, accidentally meets mobster Russell Bufalino.
Once Frank becomes his trusted man, Bufalino sends him to Chicago with the task of helping Jimmy Hoffa, a powerful union
leader related to organized crime, with whom Frank will maintain a close friendship for nearly twenty years.
Frank Sheeran, played by Robert De Niro.
Jimmy Hoffa, played by Al Pacino.
Russell Bufalino, played by Joe Pesci.
Angelo Bruno, played by Harvey Keitel.
Bill Bufalino, played by Ray Romano.
Skinny Razor, played by Bobby Cannavale.
The Irishman (also known as I Heard You Paint Houses) is a 2019 American epic gangster film directed and produced by Martin
Scorsese from a screenplay by Steven Zaillian, based on the 2004 book I Heard You Paint Houses by Charles Brandt.
It stars Robert De Niro, Al Pacino, and Joe Pesci, with Ray Romano, Bobby Cannavale, Anna Paquin,
Stephen Graham, Stephanie Kurtzuba, Jesse Plemons, and Harvey Keitel in supporting roles.
The film follows Frank Sheeran (De Niro), a truck driver who becomes a hitman involved with mobster Russell Bufalino
(Pesci) and his crime family before later working for the powerful Teamster Jimmy Hoffa (Pacino).
The film marked the ninth collaboration between Scorsese and De Niro, in addition to Scorsese's sixth collaboration with Harvey Keitel, his fourth collaboration with Joe
Pesci; his first with Al Pacino; the fourth collaboration between Pacino and De Niro; and the first collaboration between Pacino and Pesci altogether.
In September 2014, following years of "development hell", The Irishman was
announced as Scorsese's next film after Silence (2016).
De Niro, who also served as producer, and Pacino were confirmed that month, as was Pesci,
who came out of his unofficial retirement to star after numerous requests.
Principal photography began in September 2017 in New York City and the Mineola and
Williston Park sections of Long Island and wrapped in March 2018.
Scenes were filmed with a custom three-camera rig to help facilitate the extensive
de-ageing digital effects that made De Niro, Pacino, and Pesci appear younger.
With a runtime of 209 minutes, it is the longest film of Scorsese's career.
The Irishman premiered at the 57th New York Film Festival, and had a limited theatrical release on
November 1, 2019, followed by a streaming release on November 27, 2019, by Netflix.
The film received widespread critical acclaim, with praise for Scorsese's direction, the production and costume
design, editing, screenplay, cinematography, and the performances of De Niro, Pacino and Pesci.
It was named the Best Film of 2019 by the National Board of Review and one
of the top ten films of the year by American Film Institute.
The film was nominated for ten categories at the 92nd Academy Awards,
including Best Picture, and received numerous other accolades.
The film explores themes of chicago, illinois, philadelphia,
pennsylvania, based on novel or book, hitman, war veteran.
The tone is emotional.